# **Osgood Gunawan**

New York City, NY | 626-726-5957 | osgood1024@gmail.com <u>Github</u> | <u>Medium</u> | <u>personal website</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u>

## **Full-Stack Software Engineer**

Experienced in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux, Adobe Xd, Figma with a background in Computer and Cognitive Science specialized in Human-Computer Interaction. As a User Experience Designer, I am deeply passionate about creating experiences that build intersections between problem-solving and design thinking. My diverse skill set in UX/UI design, team-building, communication, debugging, and pair programming combined with a STEM background has led me to love computer science and software systems.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, SQLite, Javascript, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, Adobe XD, Figma, Bootstrap, Canva, Wireframing, Prototyping, Persona, User flows, Storyboarding, Interaction Design, User Experience Design, Ul & UX, User Testing

## **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## Project Zoo - Front End | Back End | Demo

A website where you can find project ideas or share your project with the platform.

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, comments, projects, and favorites.
- Built backend RESTful APIs service with Ruby on the Rails framework.
- Designed responsive transition animation with react spring and custom HTML/ CSS styling user interface.
- Designed the project brand logo with a graphic design platform, Canva.

### Movie Review- Github

A movie review website where users can check the review before watching the shows/movies or users can leave a review after watching.

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for movies, reviews, watchlists, and users.
- Showcased Ruby on Rails MVC architecture developed an entire website in 3 days with a fully functioning backend.
- Utilized movie DB API to pull and parse movies' data as well as dynamically display the most current information based on each user and destination.

## Oasis - Github | Demo | Research Demo

A Web app that offers or reserves space for an event.

- Initiated the idea aspect of the project.
- Implemented the user interface and user experience with fully CSS styling.
- Investigated multiple user studies to understand user needs for reserving or offering space for an event.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **GVM Networks (PT.Global Visi Media)**

Jakarta, Indonesia 07/2018 - 09/2018

UI & UX designer internship

07/2018 - 09/2

- Revamped an old project (a mobile app) that targets the market for field owners who rent out their soccer field.
- Helped to create a gamification concept to increase user-retention and marketing strategy for user engagement in the Bolalob.com point system.
- Collaborated with mentors and UX designers from WomanTalk to remodel and develop a new concept for health wellness in women for WomanTalk.com.

#### Mechanical Engineering Department at California State University, Fullerton

Fullerton, CA

Human Interactive Robotics Lab Internship

05/2015 - 08/2015

- Collaborated with teammates on projects such as assembly of the robot arm-rover-system and development of a sensor-based glove for extracting human's motion.
- Presented the final project to Southern California Conferences for Undergraduate Research (SCCUR).

### **EDUCATION**

Flatiron School Manhattan, NY

Immersive Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JS with React program

Bachelor Science in Cognitive Science with a specialization Human-Computer Interaction

02/ 2020 - 05/2020

#### **University California Of San Diego**

La Jolla, CA

06/2019

-Award: Design hackathon's (Designathon) most unique concept award rewarded \$1000 out of 28 teams.